我们干掉了美索不达米亚人
We have killed Mesopotamians!
我们干掉了亚述人
We have killed Assyrians,
迈锡尼人 闪族人
Mycenaeans, Sumerians,
但是
but...
我们一直没机会
we have never had the pleasure...
干掉
of killing...
阿卡得人
an Akkadian.
先砍手还先砍脚
Which limb do I take first?
希望神会怜悯你
May the gods have pity on you...
因为我兄弟可不会
because my brother will not.
我没事
You missed.
能当我哥算你好运
You're lucky we have the same mother.
蝎   子   王
在金字塔时代之前
Before the time of the pyramids,
东方崛起一支强悍的游牧部落
a fearsome horde came from the East...
横扫古老世界的蛮荒大地
and swept across the barren lands of the ancient world.
按照部落习俗
By the law of the horde,
他们推举强者为王
their greatest warrior was proclaimed their king.
他名叫曼能
His name was Memnon.
曼能刀法如神 武功盖世
He was the greatest swordsman the world had ever seen.
身边有一位巫师
With the predictions of a sorcerer...
能预言每场战役的胜负
who could foretell the outcome of every battle,
曼能大肆铲除异己
Memnon slaughtered all who resisted him,
幸存的对手寥寥可数
until only a brave few remained.
肃静 父王叫你们肃静
Silence! My father has called for silence!
不要讲话
Hold your tongues!
大家聚集在此
We are gathered in this place...
就应该摒弃成见
to put our differences aside.
趁着为时未晚
There is still time for us,
残存的部落
the last of the free tribes,
应该团结抵抗暴君
to stand together against this tyrant.
他有巫师协助 谁也不是他的对手
With his sorcerer at his side, no mortal can defeat Memnon.
巫师要是死掉 怎么办
And if the sorcerer were to die, what then?
现在计划太迟了点
It's too late for your schemes, pheron.
我袭击过曼能的车队
I have raided Memnon's caravans,
截断他的补给线
broken the supply lines to his troops,
但是他依旧势如破竹
but he still swept across the land like a plague.
我不会派我的部下去白白送死
I will not send my people to their deaths in a battle that can't be won.
你还有什么部下 巴煞
And what people would that be, Balthazar?
你已经一无所有
You are the ruler of nothing...
有的只是一堆石头和黄沙
but a pile of rocks and sand.
我若不是帝王
If I'm no king,
你又为何向我下跪
why are you on your knees before me?
巴煞 卫士
Balthazar! Guards!
阿卡得人
Akkadians.
还以为他们早就绝种了
I thought they were wiped out long ago.
他们是最后的阿卡得人
They are the last of their kind.
他们会送巫师上黄泉
By their hand, the sorcerer will die.
你相信这种为钱杀人的部族
You put your faith in a clan of cutthroats who kill for money?
别小看他们 他们是世代相传
They are more than that. They are skilled assassins...
训练有素的刺客
trained for generations in the deadly arts.
他们开出什么条件 父王
And what price do these mercenaries ask from us, Father?
二十颗鸡血红宝
Twenty blood rubies.
-那是我们最后的财宝 -住口
- That's the last of our treasury. - Be quiet.
要是他们铲除巫师
If these men kill the sorcerer,
你们作不作战
will you fight?
一言为定
So be it.
只要我们还有一口气在
As long as one of us still breathes,
巫师必死无疑
the sorcerer will die.
刺客
Assassin!
他
Him...
我们免费奉送
we'll kill for free.
日落前会到曼能的大本营
We can reach Memnon's encampment by nightfall.
你什么时候要把它换掉
When are you gonna get rid of that filthy beast?
别理他 他不是有意的
He doesn't mean anything by it.
-马比较快 -可是骆驼比较聪明
- Horses are faster. - But camels are smarter.
那个交给我
That one's mine.
活得自由
Live free.
死得光荣
Die well.
住手 听我说 我是祭司
Stop. Stop. Listen to me. I am a high priest of Set.
放了我 我用五种语言赐福你们
Spare me, and I shall bless thee in five different languages.
你会用五种语言尖叫
You'll scream in five different languages.
马贼 等一下
Horse thief. Wait! Wait!
喂 我没那么重
Hey! I'm not that heavy.
小心那个胖子 他在你后面
Look out for the first one! He's behind you!
不管你是谁 放我下来
Help me! Help me! Whoever you are, help me!
谢谢你 好心的人 安静
Oh, thank you. Thank you, good sir. Quiet.
我安全回去 你重重有赏
Surely you've heard of the enormous reward for my safe return.
巫师的帐蓬
The sorcerer's tent.
撤退
Back!
-让开 -别让他跑了
- Make way! - Find the other one!
你被出卖了 马沙亚斯
You've been betrayed, Mathayus.
-你知道我的名字 -还有你来的目的
- You know my name? - And why you're here.
他在帐蓬里
He's in the tent!
你 到后面去
You! Move around back!
生擒到阿卡得人
A living, breathing Akkadian.
实属难得
This is a rare pleasure.
听说你们的忍功一流
I hear you train yourselves to bear great pain.
你要是不死 别忘了教我
You must teach me this, if you live long enough.
你的威风现在跑哪去了
Not looking so full of yourself, are you now, assassin?
你  背叛自己的父亲
You... betrayed your own father?
对 他当时非常震惊
Yes. He was very shocked.
从他的表情可以看出来
You could tell by the look on his face.
我以父亲的首级
By my father's head,
向大王效忠
I pledge my allegiance.
我相信你的忠心
You have proven your loyalty, Takmet.
这个还没死
This one still lives.
漂亮
Beautiful.
带他过来
Bring him to me.
活得自由
Live free.
死得光荣 兄弟
Die well, my brother.
现在
So,
要怎么处置他
how shall this one die?
他今晚命不该绝
He shall not die tonight.
是吗
Really?
走着瞧
We shall see.
他不会死在你手上
Nor shall he die by your hand...
也不会死在你部下手上
or any hand you command.
你预见这样的景象
You have seen this in a vision?
一意孤行只会招来横祸
To ignore this would bring great misfortune.
神今晚眷顾他
The gods show him favor on this night.
只有神
Just the gods?
伤脑筋了
A puzzle then.
要送你归西 又不能亲自动手
How to kill you without using my hand or any hand I command?
厉害吧
Fascinating, isn't it?
用烟把火蚁熏出巢穴
The smoke, it causes the fire ants to abandon their homes, you see?
来享用我们的项上人头
All the sooner to feast on our naked heads.
你觉得好笑?
You think this is funny?
有一点 因为我逃得掉 而你呢
It's a little bit funny. Yes. You see, I am about to escape,
只能等死 谁叫你昨晚丢下我
while you are about to die a horrible death for leaving me to die last night.
那你还不逃
So what are you waiting for?
看到那个守卫没
You see that one up there?
他猛灌犁牛尿 要不了多久
He's been drinking that Yak piss for about an hour now, and sometime very soon...
看到没
Ahh. You see?
马贼呢
Hey! Where's the horse thief?
快点 快救我出去
All right. Come on. Get me outta here.
你  答应不杀我?
Do you, uh, promise not to kill me?
好 我答应
Yes, I promise.
记住 你是阿卡得人
Remember, you are an Akkadian.
阿卡得人说话一向算话
You make an oath, you always have to keep it, right?
没错
That's right.
答应带我走 有好处分我一份
Promise to take me with you and share in the spoils of your adventures.
什么 可以 我答应
What? All right. Fine. Yes, I promise.
搞定 不要动
All right. Now hold still.
这边有一只 好大一只
Oh, here's one. Ah. That's a big one!
哇 这只是蚁后
My! Here comes the mother.
我们要去哪
So, where are we going?
去曼能的土地 替我哥报仇
To Memnon's kingdom to avenge my brother's death.
-不准碰我的弓 -没问题
- Never touch the bow. - Not a problem.
你在叫谁
Who are you calling?
我的坐骑
My ride.
不错的骆驼
It's a nice camel.
后面很挤 麻烦你挪一挪
Not much room back here. Scoot up, please.
嘿 我们说好的
Aah. Hey! We had a deal!
没错 我没杀你  还没
That's right. And I haven't killed you... yet.
我的女巫今天看到什么
What news from my sorceress today?
看到什么
What news?
你的大军将会西征
Your armies will conquer in the West.
大败依希丝女王的军队
Queen Isis's forces will scatter to the four winds.
把消息传给各将领
Give the generals the news.
准备打最后一仗
Have them make their armies ready for the final campaign.
是的 大王
Yes, my Lord.
你认为我不择手段
You think I'm cruel, don't you?
也许你忘了外面的情形
Perhaps you've forgotten what it's like outside these walls.
残忍 无知 野蛮
Heartless, ignorant and savage.
但我能拨乱反正
But I can change that.
我会平息数百年的动乱
I will bring order after centuries of chaos.
为天下带来长治久安
An order which will last for a thousand years.
血流成河换不来和平
Rivers of blood can never bring peace.
却可以换来服从
But they can bring obedience.
那样就够了
That will suffice for now.
一旦我完成霸业
And when I have become the king of legend,
你将与我比肩而立
then you shall take your place beside me...
共享王位 同床共枕
on a throne... and in my bed.
但是 大王
But, my lord,
与你同床 我会失去预知能力
in your bed I would lose my gift of sight...
你也会失去作战的优势
and you would lose your advantage in battle.
那个时候
The day I speak of...
我已经不需要你的预知
is the day I no longer need your vision.
娥摩拉城
Gomorrah.
听我说
Let me tell you,
打家劫舍 辛苦了一天
after a hard day of looting and pillaging,
最棒的就是去娥摩拉城玩
there is no greater city than Gomorrah.
虽然所多玛城也不错
Except maybe Sodom.
可惜我不能去
I wish I could join you.
你不去?
You're not going?
相信我
Believe me,
我是很想找那些红卫队算帐
I'd like to even the score with a few of those Red Guards myself.
可是我被通缉
But with the price I've got on my head,
不可能进得去
I'd never make it through those gates.
我有信心 我们一定进得去
I have faith in you, my friend. You'll get us in.
看吧
You see?
守卫森严到连苍蝇都飞不进去
They've got the city sealed up tighter than a crab's buttocks.
我希望能帮得上忙 但我
I wish there was something I could do to help, but I-I...
你帮得上忙
Oh, but there is.
你有什么事
What business do you have here?
我来领赏的
I've come to collect a bounty.
-马贼 -我认识他
- Horse thief. Oh. - I know this dog.
这次一定让他脑袋搬家
They'll behead him for sure this time.
他没头会比较好看
He'll be all the prettier without it.
怎么回事
What happened?
我就说靠你进得来
You got us in. I knew you could do it.
给我朋友来杯最好的酒
A jug of your finest wine for my road-weary friend here.
等一下 我好像记得
Wait a minute. The last thing that...
你一记老拳
that I remember was this huge...
-挥过来 -酒来了
- Akkadian fist coming straight into... - Here's your wine, sir.
有什么需要尽管吩咐
Please, let me know if there's anything else you'd like.
还是大城市好
Ah. It's good to be back in the big city.
-帮我看着骆驼 -没问题
- Watch my camel for me? - Gladly.
你在这里做了多久
Been working here long time?
肉串好不好吃
How's the kabob?
品质保证
Merchandise of the highest quality.
由庞贝城僧侣铸造的纯钢
Virgin steel forged by the monks of pompeii.
看啊 全世界最锋利的剑
Here! Here they are! The world's finest swords.
在娥摩拉城就要佩戴好剑
Huh? You can't get respect in Gomorrah without a quality blade...
观赏鸟 肉食鸟
Birds of paradise, birds of prey.
世界上最漂亮的珍禽
The most beautiful birds in the world.
阿兵哥 看你肌肉紧绷
Hey, soldier. Those big muscles look cramped.
我来帮你松弛一下
Perhaps one of us can help you relax.
或者我们一起伺候你
Maybe all of us.
先生 我帮你带路
Mister, mister. Guide, mister.
你需要向导带路
You need a guide to find your way in Gomorrah.
好的向导会带我进曼能的宫殿
A good guide might be able to show me a way into Memnon's palace.
聪明的向导就不会
But a smart guide wouldn't,
不然你只会进曼能的地牢
or he'd be shown into Memnon's dungeon.
不在我身上
I don't have it.
想不想赚这颗
Do you wanna earn this one?
准备动手 我一半 你一半
Get ready. I'll kill half, you kill half.
好吧 都交给我
All right. I'll kill 'em all.
干脆绕路走就不要杀人了
How about we go around them and not kill anybody?
天啊 你是不是要杀我
Good Lord. Are you going to kill me?
等一下再说
Maybe later.
曼能动不动就要砍我的头
Memnon's always threatening to have my head.
不要碰
Don't touch that.
这是什么
What is it?
那是我精心泡制的魔术粉
That's my special magic powder.
魔术粉?
Magic powder?
对 魔术粉
Yeah, magic powder.
我花一大笔钱买来的中国配方
It's a Chinese formula that I procured at great expense.
研制成功的话
If I get the recipe right, it'll move mountains,
不但可以开山辟路
clear roadways in an instant...
还可以造福人群
do great things, wonderful things.
也可以为害人间
Or terrible things.
我的发明都被曼能拿来作战
Like all my inventions, Memnon will try to use it for war.
曼能在哪
Where is Memnon?
你想杀他 是吗
Oh, you mean to kill him, do you?
-对 -既然如此
- Yes. - Well, in that case,
他在练武场
I'd say he was in the training courtyard.
放手 放开我
No! Let me go!
我又没做什么
I didn't do anything!
你知道偷窃的下场
You know the penalty for thievery.
不
No!
不要
Oh, no.
No!
有刺客
Intruder!
跟我来
Follow me!
-又是你 -我怎么出去
- You again. - How do I get outta here?
穿过那扇门
Through that door.
-那是什么 -我最新的发明
- What's that? - That's one of my latest inventions.
快速运输机
It was meant to be a quick means of transportation,
不过着陆有点问题
but there was a little problem with the landings.
开门
Open!
-开门 -别碰 会启动机器
- Open! - Don't touch that. You'll set it off.
好
Right.
我的天
Oh.  Oh, my!
男人
A man.
-这是什么地方 -曼能的后宫
- What is this place? - Lord Memnon's harem.
不过他很少来 我们好寂寞
But he visits so rarely. And it gets so lonely.
别烦我 行不行
Can't you leave me alone, Thorak?
说话小心点
Watch your tongue, philos.
小心 这些是精密的仪器
Careful with those! They're delicate instruments.
曼能大人欣赏你 算你好运
You're lucky Lord Memnon has a taste for your "science,"
老家伙
you old fool.
要是我发现你和刺客有关系
If I find out you had anything to do with this intruder,
我就要你的命
I will send the executioner.
我们会让你满意
We know how to please.
-我相信 但是  -不要走
- Oh, I'm sure you do, ladies, but I... - Stay with us.
-留下来嘛 -谢谢 我赶时间
- Stay with us. - That's nice, but now's not a good time.
我们会让你美梦成真
We will make your every fantasy come true.
放箭
Kill him!
快追
After him!
Go get him!
你是要杀我 还是就这样盯着我
Well, are you gonna try to kill me or just stare at me?
吸气
Take a breath.
赞美神
Gods be praised!
你好大胆 敢碰我
How dare you touch me!
我是阿卡得人 奉命来杀你
Sorceress, I am an Akkadian hired to kill you.
不过现在 你活着对我更有用
Now, I find myself in a position where you are of more use to me alive.
别让我改变主意
Don't make me change my mind.
他说 大小不重要
And he said, it's not the size of the hump,
重要的是能耐
it is the motion of the camel.
可惜 我现在要走了
Alas, I must leave you now.
-叛徒就在那 -我的天
- There's the traitor! - Oh, great gods!
他死了
He is dead!
认命吧 臭骆驼
Just admit it, you smelly camel!
我才是你的主人 你要听我的
I am your master now! You belong to me!
他死了 死了
He's dead! Dead!
死了
Dead!
你还活着 我就知道
You are alive. I knew it!
对
Right.
我才刚跟骆驼说
I was just saying to the camel,
没人能杀死我们的马沙亚斯
"Camel, no one could kill our good friend Mathayus."
上去
Get on.
我干嘛要听你的 你不是要杀我
Why should I make it easy for you? You're sworn to kill me.
其他人会比你先死
Others will die first.
你真会安慰人
That's comforting.
你朋友是谁 曼能的巫师
So who is your friend? Memnon's sorcerer.
曼能的巫师
Memnon's sorcerer?
你疯了 我们会被她害死
Are you insane? She's going to get us all killed!
我要用她引曼能出来
Memnon will have to leave the safety of his palace to get her.
所以你先利用我 再杀我
So you're going to use me first and then kill me?
我觉得好过多了
I feel so much better.
我也可以倒过来 先杀你
I could always do it the other way around and kill you first.
我们要去哪
So where are we going?
死亡谷
The Valley of the Dead.
死亡谷?
The Valley of the Dead?
哪有人去死亡谷的
Nobody goes to the Valley of the Dead!
你以为那个名字是假的?
That's why they call it the Valley of the Dead!
等我一下
Wait for me, please!
你带十二名高手去追
Take a dozen of your best men, track him down,
杀了他
kill him...
把她带回来
and bring her back to me.
得手立刻通知我
Send me news when he's dead.
-是的 大王 -大王
- Yes, my lord. - My lord.
军中传出巫师出走的谣言
There are rumors spreading to the armies that she's gone.
-是吗 -是的 大王
- Is this true? - It is, my lord.
那就想办法压制这种谣传
Then silence them!
让士兵以为她还在这
They must believe she is here,
必须尽快
if only for a short time.
找到那个阿卡得人
And when you find the Akkadian,
送这枝箭给他
give him this from me.
我们是不是到了
Are we where I think we are?
是
Yes.
到家了
Home.
你想去哪 巫师
Where are you going, Sorceress?
急着回曼能身边
In a hurry to get back to Memnon?
不 急着离开你
No, I'm in a hurry to get away from you.
我也不会回到曼能那里
I'll never go back to Memnon.
他从小就软禁我
He's kept me prisoner since I was a child.
那晚在帐蓬 你为什么帮我
Why did you help me that night in the tent?
我知道你可以帮我逃走
I knew you were the one man who could help me escape.
要走就走 外面比这儿还危险
Run if you like. There are worse dangers out there than me.
什么叫你找不到
What do you mean you can't find it?
我知道就在附近
I know it's around here somewhere.
你在找什么
What are you looking for?
躲避沙暴的地方
Just a little place to get out of the storm.
什么沙暴
What storm?
你会看到的
You'll see.
曼能是不是没来
Memnon didn't come, did he?
他派了走狗来
Sent his maggots to do his work.
他比你想的要聪明
He's smarter than you think.
应该是懦弱
Or more cowardly.
我可不可以回家
Can I go home now?
待在这里
Stay here.
盖住
Cover up.
你们不会有事的
You'll be safe.
快看
Look, sir.
他单枪匹马来挑战
He's attacking! Alone?
太阳晒得他神智不清了
The sun has fried his brain.
取他首级者 赏金一千
A thousand duranas for the one that brings me his head.
阿卡得混蛋
Akkadian bastard!
他在哪
Where is he?
这边
This way!
你们两个先进去
You two first. Come on. Go.
踩在石头上
Stay on the stones.
跟我来
Come with me.
不要碰
Don't touch that.
懦夫
Coward!
有种就出来
Show your face!
阿卡得人
The Akkadian.
你还活着
Ahh! You are alive!
好像拍苍蝇一样 你太厉害了
You swatted them like flies! You are invincible!
告诉我 有没有办法救他
Tell me. Do you think you can save him?
他中了蝎子毒 在发高烧
His fever's high. The poison was made with scorpion venom.
就算不死  蝎子血
If he does live, the blood of the scorpion...
也会永远留在他体内
will always flow through his veins.
巫师
Sorceress.
真是奇迹
It-It's a miracle.
她救了你
She cured you.
我就知道她有办法
I knew it! I felt her magic!
她差点没命 还好有神的保佑
It almost killed her, but the gods, they were on our side.
为什么
Why?
为什么冒生命危险救我
Why would you risk your life to save mine?
因为我相信你会拯救百姓
Because I believe you can save the people.
他们不是我的问题 曼能才是
The people are not my problem. Memnon is.
你和百姓有相同的问题
You and the people have the same problem.
启禀大王 索瑞克有消息
Pardon, my lord. A message from Thorak.
阿卡得人终于死了
Finally the Akkadian is dead.
有事吗 大王
Is there something wrong, my lord?
没事
Not at all.
一切顺利
Everything is in order.
事实上 因为非常顺利
In fact, things are going so well...
所以我要把计划提前
that I'm moving up our plans.
明晚我们设宴庆祝出师大捷
Tomorrow night, we feast to celebrate our impending victory.
然后挥军扫平残余的叛逆
And then we'll drive the last of the rebels into the sea.
下去吧
Now, go.
大王
My lord,
按照惯例 巫师应该出席会议
it is customary for the Sorceress to be present at these meetings.
为什么她今天不在
Why is she not here today?
她不舒服
She's indisposed.
我希望不严重
It is nothing serious, I hope.
严重的话 你自然会知道
If it were serious, then you would know about it.
退下
Now, go!
她还活着 跟他一起 在来的路上
She is alive. She is with him and he's coming here.
去准备
Get ready.
成功了 成功了
It works! It works!
大人 能在荒郊野地看到你真好
My lady. How lovely to see you out here in this desolate place!
你快来看 我成功了
Let me show you. It works!
快点 快点
Come, come, come!
巫师大人
My lady sorceress.
你看 我成功了
You see? I worked it out.
我的中国配方 我的魔术粉
My Chinese formula. My magic powder works!
原来我需要的是硝石
All I needed was salt. Petered salt.
硝石就在这里 这里多得是
It was here all the time. This place is just full of it.
对了 你们谁有带水
By the way, do any of you happen to have any water?
你觉得这水可以喝吗
What do you think? Is it safe to drink?
本来可以
Not anymore.
太好喝了 沙岩有天然的过滤效果
Delicious. The sandstone must act as a natural filter.
安静
Quiet.
我还活着 我还活着
I'm alive! I'm alive!
目前是
For the moment.
走
Move!
刺客 神待我不薄啊
Assassin. The gods are good to me.
上次见面 你想杀我
When we last met, you offered to kill me.
现在轮到我报答你
Now I have a chance to return the favor.
你们擅闯禁地
You're trespassers here.
我们能生存全靠这里够隐秘
Our survival depends on this place being kept a secret.
只要你们活着 问题就来了
So we have a problem... as long as you're alive.
没问题 我绝对守口如瓶
No problem. I can keep a secret like no other.
我连怎么来的都不记得
In fact, I cannot remember how we got here. We took a left turn...
-太迟了 -巴煞
- It's too late for that. - Balthazar!
我们收留所有曼能的敌人
This place is sanctuary for all of Memnon's enemies.
-你应该知道 -他是个危险人物
- You know that. - This man is dangerous.
你判断错误
Your judgment is clouded.
我的判断让大家活到今天
My judgment keeps all of you alive.
这个人不可靠 我可以证明
This man cannot be trusted, and I'll prove it.
把那个女人带上来
Bring the woman to me.
谁敢碰她 就别怪我不客气
The first man to touch her will have to come through me.
正合我意
I had hoped for nothing less.
不公平
That's not fair.
打他
Get him.
不
No!
-你服不服 那你是执迷不悟 -不服
- Do you yield? Then you're a fool. - Never.
-我们是同仇敌忾的兄弟 -兄弟
- We're brothers in the same cause. - Brothers?
你会连累我们
You brought death to my people.
曼能一定会追来
Memnon will follow you.
把他的巫师抢回去
He will come for his sorceress.
没错 我认得她
Yes, I know who she is.
曼能不会罢手 除非她回去
And Memnon will stop at nothing till she's returned.
曼能有了她 会更锐不可当
He'll come swifter and deadlier once he has her.
会更肆无忌惮
Memnon will stop at nothing.
你们躲得了一时 躲不了一世
Hide here as long as you can, but believe me when I say he'll find you.
要是不阻止他 他就会血洗这块土地
And if he isn't stopped, he'll sweep across this land and kill all of you.
有谁可以阻止他
And who's gonna stop him, Akkadian?
你 你敢挑战他的百万大军
You? Will you stand alone before the fury of his armies?
敢
Yes.
-男的应该让女的 -你就没有
- A gentleman always lets a lady win. - You didn't.
三盘两胜如何
Best two out of three?
尝尝蜜枣
Dates?
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
卡珊卓
Cassandra!
我预见一个景象
I've had a vision.
曼能会追到这里 大开杀戒
Memnon will follow me here and destroy these people.
你确定
You know this?
我预见的景象
The things I see...
就像池面的浮光掠影
are like shimmers in a pond.
时隐时现 忽暗忽明
Some are certain, and some remain shadows.
不过有件事我确定
But I do know this...
曼能会率领大军 踏平此处
Memnon will release his armies and ride straight through this place.
曼能会死在我手上
Memnon will die by my hand.
阿卡得人 看来神今晚眷顾我
It seems the gods favor me tonight, Akkadian.
如果你跟曼能决斗 会死在他手上
If you face Memnon, you'll die.
那是你命中注定
That is your destiny.
我的命运由我掌握
I make my own destiny.
我需要你帮忙
I need your help.
你不能丢下我们
You can't leave us here.
冷静点 听听原因
Mathayus, don't be so stubborn. Listen to reason.
你一个人去 等于是去送死
You can't go alone. You're going to get yourself killed.
你要骑我的马上哪去
Where do you think you're going with my horse?
娥摩拉城 我们怎么劝都没用
To Gomorrah. Nothing we can say will stop him.
不带你的巫师去
Without your sorceress?
她回去了 怕连累你们
She returned to save the lives of your people.
我不会让她一个人面对曼能
I won't let her face Memnon's wrath alone.
-让开 -阿卡得人
- Step aside. - Akkadian,
你这是去送死
you're riding to your death.
如果让你单枪匹马去
If I let you ride alone,
我就沾不到光
what glory will there be left for me?
今晚我们热烈庆祝
So tonight we celebrate.
大家尽情享用
Eat and drink your fill...
明天我们奋勇杀敌
for tomorrow we ride into battle.
我差点捉到他 可惜被他跑掉
I would've captured him myself, but he ran like a coward.
连弓都不要了
He left his bow behind.
大王
My lord.
有件事造成军心动摇
There is something that is troubling our soldiers.
那就麻烦了 请说
How distressing. Pray tell.
传言女巫师已经离开了你
It's been said the sorceress is no longer by your side.
士兵不应该轻信
Soldiers will fall prey to...
无聊的宫廷传言
idle palace gossip.
我向你保证 她十分安全
You have my word, she's perfectly safe.
问题是出征在即
If the men are to fight, to die,
士兵不要口头保证
they may need more than that.
你怀疑我的话?
Do you doubt my word?
不敢 大王
It is not that, sire.
不过她是振奋军心的象征
It's just she is a symbol from which the men derive courage.
-总要眼见为真才好 -大王
- Symbols are most effective when seen. - My lord.
我奉召而来
I am here at your request.
近来身体不适
pardon my absence.
还望大王恕罪
I was not well.
我军即将大捷 令我精神一振
But our impending victory has lifted my spirit.
这样可以稳定军心了吧
Is this sufficient to placate your men?
把你预见的景象告诉他
Tell them what you see, Sorceress.
我看到我军大捷
I see a great victory.
你的敌人会自动现形
Your enemies will reveal themselves to you.
停
Halt.
里面是什么 里面是什么?
What is in the cart? "What is in the cart"?
里面  是个惊喜
Actually, it is a bit of a surprise.
为今晚的宴会助兴
A gift for tonight's festivities.
泰克麦王子吩咐的
Prince Takmet's request.
非常好
Very nice.
让我看看  这位姑娘
Well, now. Let's see that pretty little face.
去我的寝宫
Now go to my chambers.
我有事跟你谈
We have things to discuss.
请大王恕罪
My sincerest apologies, my lord.
我明白
I understand.
你胆小 懦弱
You are fearful, weak.
宴会结束
The feast is over.
养精蓄锐 准备明天出征
To bed, men, for tomorrow we conquer.
加强宫殿警戒
Fortify the palace guard.
入城比较容易
All right. That was the easy part.
-接下来怎么做知道吧 -制服守卫
- Everybody know what to do? - Cripple the guards.
-点燃火药 -想办法保住小命
- Ignite the powder. - And try not to get killed.
你怎么来了 你会受伤
What are you doing here? You could get hurt.
你也会
So could you.
待在车里
Stay in the wagon.
阿卡得人 自己小心
You watch yourself, Akkadian.
用不着担心 女士
No need for concern, miss.
我会找他算帐的 走
Oh, he's gonna pay for that.
关闭宫门 关闭所有宫门
Seal the gates. Seal all the gates.
看到你安然无恙 我就放心了
Though I'm relieved to see you unharmed,
奇怪的是 他竟然放过你
I am somewhat surprised the Akkadian didn't kill you.
他要对付的是你 不是我
He was after you. I was merely a pawn.
你怎么逃出来的
But you escaped his grasp?
略施小计
I'm not without my wiles.
这个我知道 带进来
Yes, I'm well aware of that. Bring them.
你预见 我明天就完成霸业
Tomorrow my victory is complete. That is your vision?
我说过 我有看到
As I said, I have seen it.
你有吗
Have you?
我感觉你变了
I sense a change in you.
你看起来
You seem somehow...
法力变弱
diminished.
我向你保证 我没有改变
I assure you. I am myself.
那好
Good.
一个小小的示范应该难不倒你
A small demonstration shouldn't trouble you then.
一个简单的测验
A simple test.
退下 全部退下
Now go. Everyone leave.
-我应该去哪 -停车
- Where am I going? - Stop.
在那里
It's over there.
应该在那里
Should be just there.
好家伙
Good man.
瞧瞧
Well, well.
是谁来啦
What do we have here?
一次一包
One at a time.
六个瓮 四条眼镜蛇
Six urns, four cobras.
现在
Now.
看你看不看得到
Let's see what you can see.
很好
Excellent.
现在只剩一个空的
One empty pot left now.
谁想送死
Who dies first?
我们快到了
We're almost there.
知道我看到什么 恐惧
You know what I see? Fear.
你已经失去法力
You have lost your power,
完全失去
thrown it all away.
-这是什么法术 -我的法术
- What magic is this? - My magic.
我看到你的下场 暴君
I see your fate, hollow king.
你的气数已尽
And its time has come.
看是法术厉害 还是剑厉害
You wish to test magic against steel?
我要这个女人 还有你的头
I've come for the woman and your head.
刺客和女巫
The assassin and the sorceress,
多浪漫啊
how romantic.
我一刀成全你们两个
I'll bury you both together.
就是这里 宫殿的基石
And here it is, the foundation stone.
快点 没时间了
Hurry, we're running out of time.
我已经很快了
I'm hurrying, I'm hurrying.
前无去路 后有追兵
Fire in front, palace guard at your back.
看来我的头 你是拿不走了
Looks like I'll be keeping my head after all, Akkadian.
杀了女巫
Kill the witch!
这是为你父亲
For your father.
死得好 刺客
Die well, assassin.
阿卡得人 看来神今晚眷顾我
It seems the gods favor me tonight, Akkadian.
-快点燃 -你点
- Hurry up and light it. - You hurry up and light it.
这是你的发明
This is your invention.
跟我来
Follow me.
准备进攻
Ready! Weapons!
这次完蛋了
So much for not getting killed.
接箭
Catch this.
王上万岁 万岁 万岁
Hail to the king! Hail, hail!
我就知道
I knew it from the start.
万岁 好耶
Hail! Yeah! Mathayus!
巴煞 留下来 这里百废待举
Stay here with us, Balthazar. There's much work to be done.
我要照顾我的族人
I have to look after my own people.
我相信 你会是个好帝王
You're a king now, Akkadian, and a good one, I think.
不要忘了自己的出身 背景
Don't forget how you got here or the people you came from.
我不会让我的族人蒙羞
My people will live on through me.
记住 这里随时欢迎你
Remember, there'll always be a place for you here.
-活得自由 -好好统治
- Live free. - Rule well.
记住  努比亚人会看着你 蝎子王
Remember, Nubian eyes will be watching you, Scorpion King.
我看见太平盛世
I see a time of great peace and prosperity ahead.
你怎么看得到
How is it you see this?
传说你会失去法力 一旦
Don't the legends say you'll lose your powers if you...
你能想到更好的藉口
Can you think of a better way...
来避免帝王占你便宜吗
to keep a king from taking advantage?
我的祖先也想不到
Well, neither could my ancestors.
这样的盛世又能维持多久
And how long will this time of peace last?
王上 世事无常
Nothing lasts forever, my king.
王朝也躲不过世代交替的命运
That is the destiny of all kingdoms.
那我们就自己开创我们的命运
Then we'll make our own destiny.
我曾经告诉过你
I've told you this once before
你无法控制我
You can't control me
如果你想打倒我 省省吧
If you try to take me down you're gonna break
你所做的一切根本伤害不到我
And I feel your every nothing that you're doing for me
当我还手的时候
I'm picking you out of me
你却逃跑了
You run away
我独自站着那
I stand alone inside
独自站着
I stand alone
你总是躲在你的上帝身后
You're always hiding behind your so-called goddess
以为那样我们就看不见你
So what you don't think that we can see your face
在被灭绝前还能复活
Resurrected back before the final fallen
找到出路前我不会停歇
I'll never rest until I can make my own way
我不惧怕灭亡
I'm not afraid of fading
独自站立着
I stand alone
感觉到你蜇疼了我
Feeling your sting down inside me
可我不会因此身亡
I'm not dying for it
独自站立着
I stand alone
我相信一切终将灭亡
Everything that I believe is fading
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside
独自站立着
I stand alone
现在轮到我了
And now it's my time
我的时代
Now it's my time
我梦想的时代
It's my time to dream
梦想的天空
Dream of the sky
梦想的苍穹
让我相信这个地方已经
Make me believe that this place is invaded
被我体内的毒素侵入
By the poison in me
帮助我决定是否用我的怒火烧光一切
Help me decide if my fire will burn out
在你复活以前
Before you can breathe
先复活我
Breathe into me
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside
独自站立着
I stand alone
感觉到你蜇疼了我
Feeling your sting down inside me
可我不会因此身亡
I'm not dying for it
独自站立着
I stand alone
我相信一切终将灭亡
Everything that I believe is fading
我独自站立着
I stand alone inside
我从心里感到晕眩和疲倦
I'm dizzy and weary from the heat
如同沙粒抹去时间的痕迹
As the sands erase the hands of time
与你同在简直是种背叛
Do a job with you involved This is a betrayal
我穿过山谷将他刺死
I walk through the valley and stab him to death
见到那张几乎无法忘记的面孔
I see a face I can't seem to forget
战争就是你得到的
The war you wage
无论发生什么你都得付出
Whatever that happens you pay
身体里的仇恨
Something wrong in you
使你生机勃勃
Comes alive in your hate
让你迷失自己
Lose yourself in some kind of hell
你被仇恨点燃
Left you burnin'up where you are now
你将永远无法摆脱
You'll never ever get out
无法摆脱
No
生命中的某处
Somewhere along the way
时间改变一切
Time changes everything
这场竞赛没有赢家
This race cannot be won
时间长河或蜿蜒徜徉 或奔流湍急
Some days it crawls while other days it flies
终将弥补一切 永不妥协
It feeds on our flaws It knows no compromise